# Vanessa Castilho de Carvalho | User Experience Designer

735 11th street, Miami, Florida, 33139 | **Phone**: (786)-769-6433 | **Email**: designvanessav@gmail.com

**Linkedin Profile**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vanessa-castilho-decarvalho/

Portfolio: portfoliovanessa.tech

### Summary

Data-driven professional with a career-long record of technical operations, graphic design, and UX/UI design success for a leading organization. Experienced in translating business goals into concepts, mocks, and prototypes, aligned with users' needs. Design-process focused on user requirements to deliver an optimized user experience.

#### Skills

A/B Testing, Analytics, Product Design, Quality Assurance, Scrum/Agile, Usability Testing, User Experience Development, Graphic Design, User Research, Web Design, Wireframing, Mobile Design.

### **Experience**

### Boats Group, Miami

Boats Group is an advertising and software company for the marine industry with niche titles: YachtWorld, BoatTrader.com, and boats.com combined 10 million monthly viewers, 11 languages)

### 05/2019 - PRESENT

# UX/UI Designer & Front-end Developer

- Define user requirements and build storyboards, wire-frames, user flows, prototypes, and high fidelity mocks optimized for a wide range of devices and interfaces, to demonstrate interaction concepts for the apps and portals;
- Combine the design-cycle with front-end development breaking into components and building code for each piece, creating elegant and engaging website experiences;
- Conduct extensive user research to transform inputs and behavioral data into design insights that leverage engagement;
- ❖ Ideated and developed A/B tests for the product details page targeting the email lead form. The variation boosted the conversion rate by 2.5%, resulting in more leads;
- Designed and A/B tested an iteration of the search results page. The variation augmented time on page by 18% and maximized product page views by 10%;
- Lead extensive user research to recreate a single step funnel checkout (for sale by owner) into an intuitive multi-step process. The result rocketed the desktop conversion rate, boosting the number of products listed for sale by owners.

### 04/2018 - 05/2019

#### **Website Implementation Specialist**

- Managed the delivery of over +45 fully responsive websites within a year in an Agile/Scrum environment. Handled projects from the ideation phase to design and development in a WordPress platform. Trained clients to use the system;
- Executed accessibility diagnostics of websites and implemented -design and HTML-

changes to pass accessibility tests;

- Provided detailed analysis of SEO performance of +40 websites, tailoring written content, meta tags, ALT tags, and keywords. Implemented the changes and achieved better allocation of those businesses on search results pages within 6 months;
- Designed new responsive WordPress templates for our clients to choose from, expanding sales adoption with modern and clean templates for new customers;
- Played a key role by executing branding, logo, and product redesign for website clients.

01/2013 - 10/2017
Porto Alegre Hostel, Brazil
Product Designer

- Led the user research and gathered requirements for a competitive booking website. Interviewed guests to find pain points and friction areas of the website. Designed for layout adjustments based on interview findings and website survey results;
- Developed a new intuitive website (bootstrap/JS) with an integrated booking reservation system on the cloud. The new website boosted the conversion rate by 18% within one year.;
- Produced and executed seasonal marketing campaigns, increasing revenue year over year. Created original SEO content and implemented semantic HTML;
- Performed link building strategies to improve SEO positions for targeted keywords; analyze and recommend website architecture changes;
- Created print graphics to include brochures, logos, branding, and online marketing material.

#### Education

08/2010 - 08/2014 SENAC, Brazil - Graphic Design Program

### **Technical Skills**

**Software:** Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Figma, GitHub, Google Optimize, Hotjar, Jira Optimizely, Sketch, Visual Studio.

Coding: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS Grid Flexbox, Less, Semantic UI.

# Languages

**English** - Native or Bilingual Proficiency | **Portuguese** - Native or Bilingual Proficiency **Spanish** - Advanced

#### Certificates

IBM - Enterprise Design Thinking (04/2020 - 10/2020)

Apply design thinking to complex teams, problems, and organizations.